我们现在怎么办?
What are we gonna do now?
我会想出办法的
I'll think of something.
冷掉的披萨跟温暖的小狗
-在笑什么? -鲁斯没跟你讲吗?
-What's funny? -Russ didn't tell you?
他有跟我讲工作的事 但没讲好笑的事
He told me about the job, but he didn't tell me anything funny.
-他没跟你讲彼得的事? -没 谁是彼得?
-He didn't tell you about Pete? -No. Who's Pete?
有个叫彼得的医生很沮丧
Well, it seems that this physician-type character named Pete was all depressed one day.
因为他做了些让他很内疚的事
He felt terrible 'cause he did some stuff he just couldn't get over.
-他做了什么? -他睡了五个他的病人
-What did he do? -He slept with five of his patients.
但他其实没有那么糟
But Pete wasn't the worst guy in the universe,
因为他一直很内疚
because no matter how hard he tried to forget about it, he couldn't.
违反职业道德也让他很痛苦
The guilt and sense of unprofessionalism was overwhelming.
但他心里一直有个声音
But every once in a while he'd hear a voice inside
说着:不要在意
that said, "Pete, don't worry about it.
你不是第一个跟病人睡的医生
You weren't the first licensed practitioner to sleep with one of your patients
更不会是最后一个
and you won't be the last.
更何况你还单身
Besides, you're single.
不要在意了
Let it go."
不过当他要不自责时
But then, just when he almost over the guilt with it all,
另一个声音出现了
another voice would bring him back down to reality.
说着:彼得
And say, "Oh Pete,
但是
But dude,
你是兽医
you're a veterinarian!"
小薇!
Vi!
该走了!
Let's go!
你在干嘛?
Wha-What are you doing?
-我不懂 -不懂啥?
-I don't get it. -Don't get what?
"寿衣"有什么好笑的?
What's so funny about the vegetarian man? I don't get it.
-你是说"兽医"? -对 我不懂
-You mean the veterinarian man? -Yeah, that guy. I don't get it.
他跟病人睡
He sleeps with his patients.
而他的病人都是狗跟猫之类的
His patients are probably cats and dogs and llamas and stuff.
那有什么好笑的?以前我家有狗跟猫
Why is that funny? Back home we had puppy dogs and kitty cats
我也常跟它们一起睡我觉得很温馨啊
I used to nap with all the time. I think it's sweet.
算了 不要再想了
Actually, don't worry about it, partner.
这世界还有很多其它的笑话
There are plenty of other jokes in the universe we can share.
让我们开始为今晚做准备
Let's just get ready for tonight.
这可是挣来的休假
Some well deserved vacation.
-我有一个好笑话 薇莉 -说吧
-I got a good one for you, Violet. -Lay it on me!
啊 该死!
Oh, dang!
-怎么了? -我忘了
-What? -I think I forgot it.
这样想起来的时候 我再洗耳恭听
Well that's the good thing, Daze. I'll be here if it comes back to you
10 9 8
Ten, Nine, Eight.
seven,
six,
five,
four,
three,
two,
one!
你怎么了?
What happened over there?
那个…
Well...
我是在想 现在你18岁了
I was just thinkin' that, since how you're 18 and all,
你现在会被当作成人判刑
you can be charged as an adult now, for all felonies.
也不能再点儿童餐 坐摩天轮了
Kid's meals, ferris wheels... God knows what else.
我知道
I know.
这可以让你心情好一点
But hey, this should turn that frown around.
我有邀请老板来参加派对
I've invited Boss to our party.
亲爱的黛西 很抱歉我没办法去庆祝你的生日 但我祝你有快乐的一天 -切特
你这样做实在太贴心了
It was swell of you to invite him.
哈罗?嗨 鲁斯
Hello? Oh, hey Russ.
鲁斯是打电话来祝我们假期愉快吗?
Is that Russ calling to wish us a happy vacation?
如果不是的话 他就打错电话了
Because if he's not, he's got a wrong number.
-呃… -该死的
-Uh... -Biatch.
我要问一下薇莉
I don't know. I'll have to check with Violet.
-小薇? -绝对不要
-Vi? -No fucking way.
-薇莉说不要 -薇莉说去你的不要!
-Violet says no. -Violet says fuck no!
你说我们还有更多的休假日
I thought you said we had some down time ahead.
薇莉说你一定会这样说
No, Violet told me you'd pull something like this.
她还说你也一定会这样说
Oh, yep, no kidding. She said you'd do that too.
提高工资 又说这次很轻松
Up the money and call it an easy gig.
这实在太老套了!你以为我们很笨吗?
That's textbook, Russ! What you think we are, stupid?
你也是!
Yeah! Same to you!
-真是不敢置信 -看这个 小黛
-Can you believe him? -Lookie here, Daze.
"周日芭比"有新的时装系列
Barbie Sunday has a new fashion line.
这时装会使你熠熠生辉
"Be your best in my new signature dress.
不管是在舞厅或办公室
Let them know you mean business at the disco or in the boardroom,
人人都会折服于这精致的作工
with the amazing versatility of the premiere piece,
以及极度时髦的设计
in my high-end line, of super stylish couture.
你将艳倒群雌!
Who's better than you girl?"
太棒了!
Oh man!
-这要多少钱? -300元
-How much is it? -Around 300 bucks.
-你怎么知道? -因为史黛西有买
-How do you know? -I know because Stacy Culpepper's got one,
而每个人都在讨论我们也来买
and everybody was talking about it. Let's get ours.
-我们不行 -为什么?
-We can't. -Why not?
因为我们把所有的钱都拿去缴房租了
Because we blew the money on rent again.
但还是有钱买个一件 然后也许…
Still, we might still have enough for just one dress and then maybe...
怎么了?
What?
又花光了!
Again, Vi?
在鲁斯把工作给别人之前打给他
Call Russ back before he gives the job away.
-我们来做 -但是…
-We gotta. -But...
他说是很简单的差事 不是吗?
He said it was an easy gig, right?
-对 -还提高工资?
-Yeah. -Upped the money too, didn't he?
对
Yeah.
那还有什么好犹豫的?
Then what are we waiting for?
这实在太赞了!
That's the shit!
鲁斯是我 黛西
Hey Russ, it's me, Daisy. I know what we said,
我们改变心意了
but we've changed our minds and we've, um, reconsidered your offer.
我们可以做
And we think that actually it would work out quite well because, um...
因为你打电话过来的那天….
See,the day that you talked about, we can work it.
深一点 宝贝 再深一点
Mmm... deeper, baby, deeper...
真恶心!你不应该觉得很享受的!
Ow, gross! You weren't suppose to like it!
享不享受不是重点
"Like" had nothing to do with it, princess.
你们听过这家伙了吗?
Now you guys heard about this guy?
有人偷了切特的东西
Okay, so basically there was this guy that stole some shit from Chet.
-他偷了什么? -一卡车的香水
-What did this guy take from him? -A truck full of cologne.
但是卡车上不只有香水
Now, this truck contains somethin' in addition to just cologne.
-还有什么? -一大袋的钱
-Somethin' like what? -A bag full of money.
奇怪的是 他竟然打电话给我们
The weird part is that the guy called us up
而且还有种挑衅我们
and had the stones to taunt us after he did what he did.
-真有种 -或是想找死
-Stones... -Or some kind of a death wish.
因为他给了我们他的住址
'Cause he all gave us his address.
他的名字跟电话
His name and number, was clear as day
还一直不断挑衅我们
the whole time he was fuckin' with us.
史黛西就住在他家不远处
Culpepper lives about three blocks from this dude.
她观察了一下
She's checked him out.
说他早上出门 下午才回来
Says he leaves in the morning, comes back in the afternoon.
等他回来时 你们就等着他了
When he comes home, you'll be waiting for him.
就这样
And that's that.
房东会帮我们把门打开
The landlord's on our team, so the door will be open.
-最好是 -别担心 一定会开
-Better be. -Relax. The door will be open.
而且你们也不用担心引起噪音
And you don't have to worry about the noise either.
-为什么? -那栋房子几乎没人住
-Why not? -The building's almost empty.
因为要改建还什么之类的
Switching over the condos or some kinda gentrificational kind of shit.
你确定他只有一个人?
You sure this guy was working alone, Russ?
很确定 房东说他都是一个人
Pretty sure. Landlord said the guy's a loner.
明天去做
This happens tomorrow.
-你们可以做到吗? -当然可以
-Can you handle it? -'Course we can handle it.
配置图?
You got the specs?
没问题了吗?
Now we good?
没问题了
Yeah, we good.
走吧 小黛
Come on, Daze.
你们知道周日芭比要推出新洋装吗?
Hey you guys hear about Barbie Sunday's new dress?
-知道 -确定一下而已
-Yeah we know. -Just checkin'.
小黛!
Daze!
啊?
Yeah?
生日快乐!
Happy Birthday!
谢了 鲁斯
Thanks, Russ.
如果多注意一下你的伙伴 你搞不好还可以看到下一个
If you keep an eye on your partner, you might be around see your next one.
去死吧!鲁斯!
Fuck off, Russ!
问她有关萝丝的事
Ask her about Rose.
再说一次:去死吧!鲁斯!
I said fuck off, Russ!
谁是萝丝?
Who's Rose?
我以前的搭档
My old partner.
-我还以为我是你唯一的搭档 -不好意思
-I thought I was your only... -Sorry Daze.
那她怎么了?
Well, what happened to her?
-死了 -怎么死的?
-She died. -How?
-被枪杀 -怎么被枪杀的?
-Got shot. -How?
就普通的枪杀
Usual way.
有人对准她 扣下板机
Somebody pointed a gun at her and pulled the trigger.
-谁? -这很复杂
-Who? -It's complicated.
-这样就说得通了 -为什么?
-Well, it all kinda make sense now. -Why?
你有时候会在睡梦中说她的名字
You talked about her in your sleep sometimes.
我会?
I do?
嗯
Yeah.
睡梦花朵
-小薇? -在这
-Vi? -Yeah, man.
我等不急拿到衣服了
I can't wait until we get the dresses.
拿到后 我们就会有不同以往的新人生
Things are gonna change for us after that.
对呀!
Oh, hell yeah!
-需要上锁吗? -不 用这个
-Do we need to chain it up? -Nah, this will do.
谁碰谁就死
-没问题? -没问题
-Cool? -Cool.
这是我最后一次跟你讲这件事
This is really the last time, I'm gonna say this to you.
以及跟你讲话
Okay? Or anything else.
不要再寄任何东西给我我…
I don't want you to send me anything anymore. I don't...
我把那些花都丢了
I threw out those flowers.
你做什么都无法弥补
You can't fix it.
我实在受够你了
And I'm really... done with you.
我不想看到你或听见你
I don't want talk to you again. I don't want to hear from you again.
只想要你离我远一点
I want you to leave me alone.
你不知道怎么弥补
Please, okay? You don't know how to fix this.
你无法弥补
You can't fix it.
你…毫无头绪
You... have no clue.
离我远一点就对了
Just... leave me alone.
我再也不想跟你有瓜葛
I don't ever wanna hear from you again.
当锁转动的时候叫醒我
Wake me up when the latch turns.
但是如果…
But what if...
这看就知道不是什么危险份子的住处
This isn't exactly the residence of a renegade, Daze.
但是…
But...
保持醒着就对了 好让我去梦那件洋装
Just keep a lookout while I go and dream about a dress.
他
我的天!是这个人吗?
Oh my God! Is that the guy?
-这是怎么回事? -不知道
-What's going on? -I don't know.
-他怎么不拿走我们的枪? -不知道
-Why didn't he take our guns or nothin'? -I don't know.
-我们应该叫醒他 还是直接杀了他? -小黛 我不知道
-Should we wake him up or just pop him? -I don't know Daze.
嗨!你们好
Hey, girls.
如果你们饿的话 冰箱里有吃的
There's stuff in the kitchen if you're hungry.
-你知道我们为何而来吗? -知道 我在等你们
-Do you know why we're here? -Yes, I've been expecting you.
我想你有些误解
I think there must be some sort of misunderstanding.
我们不是来帮你打扫 整理衣服
We're not here to clean your bathtub, or...
或来取悦你的
organize your closets, or make you happy.
真的?
Really?
对
Yeah.
我们是来杀你的
We're here to kill you.
那我没有误解
Then there's no misunderstanding at all.
你介意我跟伙伴讲一下话吗?
Do you mind if I have a word with my partner?
等一下小黛 去搜他身
Wait a sec. Search him, Daze.
他没问题
He's clean, Vi.
过来
Come on then.
-这跟我们计划的不一样 -我知道
-This isn't go much like we pictured it, Vi. -Yeah, I know.
我以为这只是件普通差事
I just wish it more like a normal job.
但现在却变得很奇怪
Now it's weird.
我从没跟要下手的对象讲过话
I never really talked to a job before.
这也许是个测验
This might be some kind of test.
做个职业妇女 每件事都像测试
Everything's a test when you're a career woman.
没错
Damn right.
而且那些衣服可不是免费的
And those dresses aren't gonna buy themselves.
-我想到了! -什么?
-I got it! -What?
-我知道该怎么做! -什么?
-I know we could do! -What?
我们什么都不要想的一走进去就大扫射
Why don't we just go in there, blasting without thinking about it?
这样我们就不会顾虑有的没的
That way, we won't have to think about it.
甚至可以闭上眼 因为那么近的距离不会射偏
We don't even have to look either, because we're never gonna miss it that distance.
这可是个天大的好点子!
It's a good plan, Daze. A real good one!
-真的吗? -真的
-You think so? -Totally.
好
Cool.
-但是不要瞄得太高 -为什么?
-But don't aim too high. -Why not?
这样才不会射到那小鸟
We don't want to hit that little bird.
说得对
Oh, yeah. Good thinkin'.
准备好了吗?
Okay, ready?
-好了 -上吧!
-Ready. -Let's do it!
要吃点心吗?
Who wants a snack?
但小心烫
Be careful they're hot.
呃…不用了
Um... no thank you.
-你不喜欢饼干吗? -喜欢 但是…
-Don't you like cookies? -Yeah, but...
我现在有点内疚
I feel kind of bad now.
-不要太过度反应了 -是燕麦口味吗?
-Don't be ridiculous. -Are those oatmeal?
谢谢
Thanks, mister.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
你有在里面掺了什么吗?
Wait a minute, did you put something in these?
不然你表情怎么这样?
Why are you looking at us funny?
不不不
No, no, no...
只是我没想到来的会是你们这样的人
It's just that you girls aren't what I expected.
我们也没想到会有这样的目标
We didn't picture you either.
人生就是这样才有趣
Keeps life interesting I guess.
你有牛奶吗?
Do you have any milk?
插嘴一下
I hate to interrupt or anything, but...
你们是不是该重新装上子弹?
don't you think you girls had better reload?
你到底是有什么问题?
Excuse me, but what is your deal?
我不想谈这个
I'd rather not discuss it.
-为什么? -因为这是我的私事
-Why not? -That's my business, that's why not.
到底是有什么大不…
What's the big...
我还以为他们会派专业的来
I thought for sure they'd send professionals.
我们就是!
They did!
那又为什么要问这些?
Then why does it matter what I don't want to discuss?
如果你是我们的话 你不会在意吗?
Wouldn't you be curious if you were us?
如果你要子弹 街角那边有卖
There's a place around the corner if you need more ammo.
-我们有子弹 -那就快点下手
-We got ammo. -Then let's get this show on the road.
等一下会有人来
Expecting company.
-什么人? -我不想说
-What kind of company? -I'd rather not say,
但他们来的时候 我们最好不在这里
except to say we probably don't wanna be here when they arrive.
-他们?谁是"他们"? -你是来面试我 还是来暗杀我?
-They? Who's "they"? -Is this an interview or a hit?
算了算了你还有饼干吗?
Whatever man. You got anymore cookies?
也许有吧
Maybe, maybe not.
这样吧 如果你杀了我 我就告诉你哪里还有饼干
How about this? If you shoot me, I'll tell you where they are.
-而且还会把食谱给你 -死了怎么做这些?
-And I'll throw in the recipe. -How are you gonna do that dead?
-杀了我就知道了 -哈哈 好难笑
-Start shooting and find out. -Hardy har har.
失陪一下 我要跟同事说个话
Excuse me. I need to confer with my colleague.
-还要? -对 还要
-Again? -Yeah, again.
不要担心 这次我不会乱跑
Don't worry. I won't move this time.
我会坐在这里不动
I'll be right here when you get back.
我们还是会杀了他
I know we gotta off this guy, 'cause that's what we gotta do.
但我想知道他为什么想死
But I don't wanna do it until I know why he wants us to do it.
他一定有什么秘密 但会是什么呢?
I mean, something's wrong here. What is this, Daze?
一个人不会去抢劫一卡车的香水跟钱
I mean a guy doesn't just up and hijack a truck chuck full of cash and cologne
只为了让自己被杀要死的方法很多
to get himself rubbed out. There are other ways.
我很想知道他的故事 但这样会让我们很难下手
I want this guy's story, but getting it would just make our job harder.
因为这会让事情改观
I mean it changes everything.
所以香肠工厂里养的猪才都没名字
That's why they don't name any of the pigs on a sausage farm.
所以我们不应该再继续跟他讲话了
And for that reason, I don't think we should talk to him anymore.
这会很难 他很有趣
That's gonna be tough, He's interesting.
-这倒是 -而且那些饼干…
-He sure is. -And how about those cookies?
我的天!
Oh man!
你有吃过那么美味的东西吗?
Have you ever had anything like that in your whole life?
如果我们很有钱 而且不用杀他的话
If we were rich, and didn't have to kill him,
就可以雇用他 专门为我们做饼干
we could pay him, just to make those cookies for us all the time.
而且如果他不只会做饼干呢?
Hell, what if the cookies are just the tip of the iceberg?
要是他还会做巧克力蛋糕怎么办?
What if he makes brownies?
我们会变得超胖 但会超值得
We'd get so fat, but it'd be so worth it.
还是像之前说的那样做好了
Anyway, let's just like we said before.
走进去就扫射
We'll just run in there blasting.
-你有带弹药吗? -没有
-You bring anymore ammo? -Nope.
你刚刚不是说还有?
I thought you said you had some more.
我只是想要显得专业 所以才说有
Nah, I just wanted to sound pro and say I did.
又不是像要对付 抢了老板夜店的
It's not like we were facing five or six jokers
那五六个蠢蛋
who shotgunned one of Chet's nightclubs.
而且我想要为洋装省点钱
Besides, I was tryin' to save up for the dresses.
从没玩过这个
Never got the hang of these.
除非这是你的死前遗愿 否则我不会费心去练这个
Unless it's high on your bucket list I wouldn't sweat it.
那地方在哪?
Where's that place again?
什么地方?
What place?
你说可以买到子弹的地方
The place, where you said we could get the bullets.
你不是说还有?
I thought you had some.
我搞错了
Well I was mistaken.
我有一把不错的菜刀
I've got a pretty good steak knife.
只是给个建议
Just trying to help.
从大门走出去后 靠右走
You go out the front door, you hook a right,
然后走三个街区 就会在你这边
then walk three blocks straight down. It's on this side of the street.
很好找的
You can't miss it.
-我去 -为什么不是我?
-I'll go Daze. -Why can't I?
因为你看起来才12岁 而且我有身份证
Because you look 12, and I've an ID.
在这样的地方他们搞不好会检查
They might actually check in this part of town.
好好监视他 还有记住我刚才说的
Just keep an eye on him while I'm gone, and remember what I said.
没问题
Okay.
你们还需要什么吗?
You guys need anything?
没有
No, we're good.
你们做朋友多久了?
So how long have you two been friends?
我不应该再跟你讲话了…
I'm not supposed to really talk to you anymore, so...
啊!你有个电话留言
Oh, wait! I think you got a phone message.
我只说这句话 现在开始就闭嘴了
But that's all I'm sayin'. Now I'm gonna zip.
你有一个留言
You have one new message.
这是我最后一次跟你讲这件事
This is really the last time I'm gonna say this to you.
以及跟你讲话
Okay? Or anything else.
不要再寄任何东西给我我…
I don't want you to send me anything anymore. I don't...
我把那些花都丢了
I threw out those flowers.
你做什么都无法弥补
You can't fix it.
我实在受够你了
And I'm really... done with you.
我不想看到你或听见你
I don't want talk to you again. I don't want to hear from you again.
只想要你离我远一点
I want you to leave me alone.
我和小薇成为朋友很久了
Me and Vi have been friends a pretty long time.
大概有三年了
Maybe three years.
什么?
What?
你问我们做朋友多久了
You asked how long we've been friends a minute ago.
对
Oh yes...
没错…
Alright.
-我们是在医院认识的 -医院?
-We met in a hospital. -In a hospital?
对
Yeah.
在雷辛顿市的布偶医院 你知道那间吗?
It was that dull hospital over on Lexington. Know it?
不
No.
我们是医生…外科医生
We were doctors. I mean, surgeons.
薇莉一直叫我说外科医生
Violet tells me to say surgeons.
而且医院的工作不会让我做恶梦
Working in the hospital never gave me bad dreams, that's for sure.
之后我们就成为好朋友了
Anyway, she's my best friend ever.
我有时候会担心她就是了
I kinda worry about her sometimes though.
有一半的时候 我希望可以更像她
Half the time, I wish I was more like her.
但…
And then...
什么?
What?
不知道
I don't know.
她让我想起我的女儿
She reminds me of my daughter.
答录机那个就是她?
Is that her on the phone machine?
但那不重要
But it's not important.
其实是重要…
It is, but...
但不要在意这件事
don't let it distract you.
-那是什么? -什么是什么?
-What's with that? -What's with what?
你们衣服上的数字
The numbers you two wear.
-这个? -对
-These? -Yes.
那是我们的阶级
Oh, that's our rank.
我是杀手9号 薇莉是杀手8号
Officially I'm killer number Nine and Violet's killer number Eight.
要怎么升级?
And how do you move up?
杀人 小薇说这比在办公室工作好
Makin' hits. Vi says it beats dead entry.
谁是杀手一号?
Who's number one?
没人看过他
No one's ever seen him.
但他曾经只用指甲刀
But he once killed three ninjas...
就杀死三个忍者
with a fingernail file.
薇莉的长征
谁?
Who's this?
有间店只离你两个街区远 外表看起来像五金行
There's a place about two blocks up from you. It looks like a hardware store.
如果说关门了 那只是骗人的
If it's closed, that's only what the sign says.
等等 我想尿尿
Hold on, hold on. I gotta take a piss.
不然哩?
What else is it?
为什么每次我要尿尿 你就也要尿?
How many time every time I take a piss you gotta take a piss?
-哪有每次 -就是每次
-Not every time -You do man. Every single damn-
每次我要尿 你就也要尿!
Every single time I gotta take a piss, you gotta take a piss!
喂!当站在男人旁边尿尿的时候 你不该往下看!
Hey, you're not supposed to look down when you're peeing next to another man, okay?
-我才没看 -你现在就在看!
-I'm not looking. -You're lookin' now, and I saw you look down!
-我在看你的脸 -你干嘛看我?
-I'm lookin' at your face. -My man, why are you looking at me all?
有时候我真的会怀疑你
Dude, you get me worried about you sometimes.
你难道不懂一点尿尿的规矩吗?
Don't you know pee etiquette man?
死亡之门 希望她快点
Let's hope she hurries.
有什么好急的?还有谁要来?
What's the big deal? Who's comin' over?
这不重要
It's not important.
我又不是问你把钱藏在哪
It's not like I'm asking you to tell me where you stashed that money or anything.
因为我做了一些事 所以等等会有人来
I'm expecting company because of something else I did.
做了什么?
What else did you do?
我抢劫了某人
I robbed somebody.
除了我们老板之外的人?
Somebody else that's not our boss?
对
Yeah.
谁?
Who?
-唐尼达夫 -我的天…
-Donnie Daffo. -Oh, my...
所以你的很想被杀?
Then you really are serious about getting yourself killed?
我想他们也是今天来
I figure it's people who visit me today as well.
这世界真小 我跟小薇恨死他们了
Small world, 'cause uh... me and Vi hate those guys' guts.
两个月前 薇莉遇到他们
Two months ago Violet ran into them,
他们把她锁在垃圾箱
and they locked her in a dumpster.
让她变得失魂落魄
It looked like someone had taken the life out of her.
他们只有这样?
Is that all they did?
锁在垃圾箱?
You mean, lock her in that trash can?
她只有说这个
Well, yeah, I mean that's all she told me.
不然他们还能做…
What else would they...?
鲁斯真是个蠢蛋
Russ is such an ass.
还自以为很聪明
Thinks he's smart, but he's not.
这次没话要说了?
Nothin' to say this time?
也许你还是学到了教训
Maybe you learned your lesson after all.
把我的话转告给你老板
Well I got somethin' for you to tell your boss.
他一定被现在的经济环境搞到快破产了
In this fuckin' economy that chicken shit must be pretty hard up
因为他竟然要派妓女来做男人的工作
to send a little cunt like you, to do a man's job.
晚点再操你
Fuck you later!
你要寻找的五金行就在这转角
-嗨 -我们已经关店了
-Hi. -We're closed. What do you want?
-我不知道你在说什么 -你知道
-I don't know what you're talkin' about. -Yeah you do.
后面的门
The black door in the back.
非常感谢
Much obliged.
需要什么?
How can I help you?
快点 快点!
Let's go, let's go! Come on.
检查一下那个箱子
Move fast. Check out those boxes right there.
快!
Let's go, move on.
但是 你是寿衣!
"But dude! You're a vegetarian!"
-看到了吗? -喔～
-See? -Oh...
不!拍一下
Nope! Slap.
1 2 3 4 拇指大战开始!
One, two, three, four, I declare a thumb war. Battle!
接下来是拍手游戏
Alright, pattycake.
-你先! -不
-No, you go first! -No...
你先这样 再这样
...you do this, and then this.
嗨
Hey!
看看这是谁
Look who's here?
我们刚刚有看到你朋友
We just saw your stupid little girlfriend.
教训了她一下
Had to tell about herself.
你真应该看看她的表情
You should see her face.
光这个早上我们就要解决几个蠢货
Just this mornin' we had to whack out a couple clowns.
而且我们很乐意做
Yeah, we took our time doin' it too.
你的朋友看起来比这两个同性恋加起来还恐惧
Your stupid little girlfriend looks scareder than both those faggots put together.
即使他们已经怕得要死
Even when things were gettin' ugly for them.
站到一旁
Step aside jailbait!
要不然我们来看看接下来你会怎样
Or don't... if you wanna be a tough guy and see what happens to you.
黛西 照着他们说的做
Do it. Do as they say, Daisy.
我想问你们一些事
Can I ask you fellas something?
-还是算了 -问啊
-Nah, forget it. -Come on.
什么?
Excuse me?
拜托
Please.
-每个人! -拜托
-Everybody! -Please.
非常好
Very good!
但你们要先把枪收起来
But I won't get into it until you holster the hardware!
-为什么? -这样你们才不会累
-Why would we do that? -So you don't get tired.
-你认为我们是白痴吗? -你们当然是白痴
-What do you think we are, stupid? -Off course I think you're stupid.
这就是问题
That's the point.
因为你们会很难理解接下来我要讲的话
You're gonna have enough trouble keepin' up with what I'm gonna tell you as it is.
要是累的话 就会更难理解了
If you're tuckered out too, we'll be wasting everybody's time.
你们也不想要浪费时间吧?
You don't want mama's good wisdom going to waste, do you?
你们的手已经开始酸了吧?
Heck, I'd be surprised if your arms aren't burnin' already
都对准我们那么久了
from keeping us at gun point so long.
我们身上又没枪 到底在怕什么?
I mean, it's not like we're packing or anything. What are you afraid of?
舒服点了吧?
That better?
-我刚刚说到哪? -你要问我们事情
-Alright, where was I? -You were gonna ask us something.
对!
Oh, that's right! Thanks!
我的问题是…
Okay. So... here it goes.
我的朋友体重大概45公斤
My partner weighs in at about 95 pounds, right?
而你们一起的话 大概可以推动500公斤
And together you guys are pushing half a ton, give or take, correct?
所以当你们把她塞进垃圾箱的时候 应该不会碰到麻烦吧?
So... did you need much help stuffing her in that garbage can?
现在…
Now...
我通常不跟你们这样的人讲话
I usually don't talk to people like you in the first place,
但如果要我讲什么的话
but... if I did that sort of thing,
我会说 你们这些小女孩真该有自己的电视节目
I would say that you girls should have your own TV show.
而那节目该叫"唐尼与她的女人"
And that you should call that program "The Adventures of Donnie's Bitches".
不过就像我刚刚讲的
But like I said at the top,
我通常不跟你们这样的人讲话
I usually don't talk to people like you.
因为跟你们这样的人讲话 实在没意义
Because talkin' to people like you doesn't make much sense.
"这样的人"?
What do you mean, "People like us"?
"这样的人"是怎样的人?
What the hell kind of people are we?
死人
Dead ones.
什么?
What?
有找到子弹 但现在又没了
Found some bullets, but now I might be out again.
你有没有听到?
I don't know about you partner... I think I'm hearin' somethin'.
听到什么?
Something like what?
内出血舞曲!
The internal bleeding dance!
-我需要帮忙 -我来了!
-I could sure use some help too. -You got it, partner!
-我要那个胖的! -每个都嘛很胖!
-Move! I want the fat one! -They're all fat, biatch!
先生
Say mister,
你知道还可以上哪买子弹吗?
you got any other leads on where I can get some more bullets?
说来话长 但那地方变成凶案现场了
That other place got turned into a crime scene. Long story.
快想想
Just do some thinkin' on it, okay?
还有别人要来?
Are you expectin' anybody else?
确定?
Are you sure?
也许是唐尼的后援
It might be backup for Donnie's crew.
也许他们要来检查 跟我们一样
Maybe they're supposed to call in. You know, like we do.
那为什么不直接进来?
Well why didn't they just come right in. Everybody else has?
不知道但不管怎样 我现在没子弹了
I don't know. Whoever the hell it is, I'm out of bullets again.
我去开门
I'll get it.
等等 如果真的是唐尼的人怎么办?
What? Wait but... what if Donnie's other guys?
-我有心理准备了 -我还以为你想要我们来动手
-I know what they'll do. -I thought you wanted us to kill you.
你在忌妒吗?
You jealous?
-一点点 -走逃生梯 我来拖延
-Kinda. -Now take the fire escape. I'll stall.
要不然等他们看到这现场 会杀了我们每一个人
Otherwise they're gonna kill us all after they see what happened in here.
走!
Go!
-跟我们一起走! -不
-Well you should come too! -No. No I shouldn't.
这样我才可以帮你们拖延
This way I'll buy you some time. Go!
拜托
Please.
快走!
Go! Go!
你没事吧?我听到些声音
Everything okay in there? I thought I heard something.
没事 朵丽斯
It's fine... Dolores.
-你好吗? -我真的有听到
-How have you been? -I thought I heard something.
我也有听到 很像又是从楼上传来的
You know, I did too. Sounded like it was coming from upstairs again.
我很确定是从这里
I was sure it was coming from here.
-你有问隔壁吗? -你真的确定没问题?
-Did you try next door? -Are you sure everything's okay in there?
对
Yes.
我现在有事要忙
I really should go now, Dolores.
你多保重
You take care.
-但… -朵丽斯
-Well ain't... -Dolores!
朵丽斯
Dolores...
多保重
Take care.
等等 来了!
Okay, you ready? Go!
115警局 这是米诺却警官
115th precinct, Officer Minocha speaking.
我隔壁的公寓有一些不对劲
There's something wrong in the apartment down the hall from me.
我们还是要解决他 你知道吧?
We're gonna have to take care of him too, you know.
知道
I know.
-我们应该现在下手 -为什么
-I think we should do it now. -Why?
他在睡觉 这样比较仁慈
He's sleeping. It'll be merciful.
我们不是没子弹?
Ah, I thought we were outta bullets again.
是没了 但我还可以再出去买
We are, but I can run out and go get some more somewhere real quick.
就算有子弹 我们也不能现在动手
We couldn't even do it now even if we had the bullets.
-为什么? -不知道…
-Why not? -I don't know.
他说他想看自己是怎么死的
He said, he wanted to see it coming.
-什么时候说的? -你不在的时候
-When? -While you're out.
-他有说别的事吗? -像什么事?
-Well did he say anything else? -Like what?
像为什么他那么想死?
Like, why he wants to check out so bad?
-说了一点 -然后?
-A little. -Well?
他得了癌症
He's… got bad cancer.
我得的是胰脏癌 而且已经扩散了
It's in my pancreas and spreading.
要死的话 我不想要慢慢而死
I'm going to die and I'd rather not take the scenic route.
我想甚至也没有人爱他 这实在太可怜了
I don't think he has anybody who loves him either, which must be even worse.
我们应该去参加他的葬礼
We should think about going to his funeral.
因为这样至少还有人去
You know, just so there's someone there.
什么?
What?
到头来 唐尼还是会派其余的手下
At the end of the day, Donnie'll send the survivin' members
来完成这件事
of his squad to finish the job either way.
所以如果我们不做 还是会有别人
So if it's not us doin' this, it'll be somebody else.
反正他是死定了!
And besides, this guy's dead already!
所以由我们下手的话还会比较好
In fact, it's way better if we're the ones to do it.
因为不像唐尼那些人
Because unlike Donnie's punks,
我们不会折磨他八 九个小时
we're not gonna torture him for eight or nine hours first.
你有听到什么吗?
Did you hear somethin'?
话说你是怎么了?你看起来一团糟
What happened to you anyway? You look a little mussed up.
这徽章又是怎么回事?
What's with the heat shield?
-这个? -嗯啊
-This? -Yeah.
我被任命为警官
I've been deputized.
-我是认真的 小薇 -好吧!
-I'm serious, Vi. -Fine!
我买弹药发生了一个小插曲
I had a little incident while I was out getting the bullets.
-你想说说吗? -你有兴趣吗?
-Do you wanna talk about it? -Are you interested?
一直都有
Always.
当我刚拿到子弹
So the second I get the lead,
三个抢匪冲了进来
three desperados stormed in and hold up the spot.
一开始我打算躲起来 好等这件事结束
First I'm thinking, I'm just gonna lay low in aisle three and let this shit be.
然后有人看到我
Then, one of them sees me
兴起了也抢劫我的想法
and gets the bright idea that they should rob me too.
所以我开始提醒他们
So I proceeded to inform the perp and his pals
他们有可能会死得很难看
of the multiple ways in which they might violated their mothers.
当他们在思考我哪里来的胆
So while they're trying to figure out where I got the balls,
警察来了
the cops show up.
是因为这地方有警铃?
Was it because the place had a silent alarm?
不
No.
是因为警察运气好?
Was it because the cops just got lucky?
当然不!
Hell, no!
因为那地方就在警局隔壁
This place is a stone's throw from the 115th precinct.
想起这件事后
So the minute I remembered that little detail,
我开始思考两件事
I'm thinking one of two things:
这些强匪要不是白痴 就是疯子
These desperados are either stupid, or crazy as all hell.
不管是哪个 他们被逮捕了
Whatever the case, the cops apprehend the whole crew,
而一个黑人问我有没有事
and then one of the fuzzy-wuzzies asks me if I'm okay.
而我就说:警官
So I said, "Officer,
是什么让你觉得我不是抢匪?
how do you know I wasn't in on it?
是什么让你觉得一个女人不能抢劫?
What makes you think a girl can't be in on it?"
接着我听到…
Next thing I hear is...
碰 碰 碰!
The guy behind the register flips and starts shooting at the perps.
有人从柜台后跳出来 开始射击那些抢匪
原来他有在柜台藏枪 好预防抢匪
It seems he had a gun beneath the counter took the robbery personally.
长话短说
Long story short,
每个人都吃了一两颗子弹
just about everybody ended up taking a slug or two,
除了我
except for yours truly.
这就是我如何得到这徽章的
That's how I got this one's shield on me.
从一个胖猪上被弹飞 掉到我身上这可是真的
It was blasted off a porker and just landed there. Scout's honor.
为了谨慎起见
Anyway, right about then, I thought it may be prudent
我就从后门离开了
to exit the premises through the rear.
有时候 你就是找不到子弹
Some days, you just can't get a bullet to save your life.
这世界有那么多国家…
And here of all places.
该死的 这里可是美国耶!
I mean, shit, this is America right?
那衣服怎么那么脏?
But, how'd you get so dirty?
我在巷子里踩到香蕉皮
I slipped on banana peel in the alleyway comin' back.
我们去看那些衣服吧
Let's go see about those dresses.
你们时间消磨的怎样?
How are you girls holding up?
还可以
Fine.
还可以 但我们又没子弹了
Fine. We're out of bullets again though.
怎么不用这些人的枪?
Why don't you use one of those guy's guns?
他们有很多的样子
They seem to have plenty.
我怎么没想到?
Why the hell didn't I think of that?
他们有好多喔!小黛!
These guys got everything Daze!
甚至还有小到可以放到皮包里的
Even a little Glock for your purse. You know the blue one?
这根本就是圣诞节!
It's like Christmas!
拿到了 该死的
I got you... Sucker!
选一个吧
Take your pick mister.
你帮我决定好了
Why don't you decide?
我看看…
Okay, let's see...
小黛 我要用点38
I'm gonna go with a .38, Daze.
你准备好了吗?
Alright, are you ready mister?
好了
Sure.
要下手了
Okay. Here goes nothin'.
哈哈 好难笑
Hardy har har.
什么
What?
你闹够了没?
Are you done yet?
说什么啊?
Come again?
我说:你闹够了没?
I said, "Are you done yet?"
你到底在说什么?
What are you talking about?
你不是真的要动手吧?
You weren't seriously gonna do it, were you?
我当然要
I most certainly was.
用那个?
With that piece?
对啊
Yeah.
-随便你 -为什么不能?
-Suit yourself. -Well why shouldn't I?
这样不专业
It's unprofessional.
为什么?
How's that?
监识科学
Forensics.
-监识科学? -对啊
-Forensics? -Yeah.
监识科学 弹道学
Forensics. Ballistics.
他们可能会把事情搞混
There's a real good chance
如果我们用那把枪杀人的话
those dorks would foul everything up for us if we do it like this.
唐尼有可能会得到功劳
I mean Donnie's guys can even wind up with the credit
因为那是唐尼的枪
if they traced the gun and...
然后老板就会拒绝付钱
boss'll try to weasel out of payin' us.
最糟的是 这里的尸体可能都会被当成我们杀的
Even worse, we might get blamed for every corpse in here.
而老板就会耻笑我们造成那么多不必要的伤亡
And boss'd chaft us to the hilt on account of unnecessary roughness.
还挑起了帮派战争
Not to mention the gang war we might've already started.
而且我们还不能用他们的子弹
And it's not even like we can switch out the bullets,
因为口径跟我们的枪不符
because the calibers won't begin to match the ones on our stylin' rods.
所以如果你真的动手的话,
So, like I said, you can do it your way if you want to, but...
我们就会看起来不够专业
We risk looking on professional and getting screwed...
也失去了那些漂亮衣服
out of a couple of hot dresses.
想得很周到 监识科学真的很麻烦
Good thinkin', Daze. Forensics will fuck you.
你也可以这样思虑周全的 小薇
You would've thought of it too, Vi.
-也许吧 -我需要抽根烟
-Yeah, maybe. -I need a smoke.
你抽烟
You do that?
你什么时候开始抽烟的?
When did you start doin' that?
不知道
I don't know.
你从哪里拿来的?
Where did you get those?
从那些人身上
Off one of those guys.
你在意我抽烟吗?
You mind if I smoke in your place, mister?
是
Yeah.
-"是 在意"或"是 可以"? -"是 在意"
-Yeah you mind or yeah it's okay? -Yeah, I mind.
事实上 还是随便你好了
Actually, do what you like.
反正也没什么差别了
It doesn't matter anyway.
我会去外面抽
I'll take it out to the stairs.
薇莉 记得把你的指纹擦掉
Oh and Violet, you might wanna wipe your prints off those pieces.
然后把枪放回他们身上
Put 'em back on the fellas.
太棒了 小黛
Sounds good, Daze.
过来坐 我想给你看样东西
Come on sit down. I wanna show you something.
如果常清理耳朵的话 你就可以变成百万富翁
You know you'd probably a millionaire if you cleaned your ears out more often.
最好是
Nuh-uh!
给你
Here.
你有什么要跟我讲的吗?
Now what were you going to tell me?
你有一个秘密…
You had a secret...
要跟我讲
you were going to tell me.
我想问你
Can I ask you somethin'?
为什么她会如此恨你?
Why is she so mad at you?
-她是你朋友 你告诉我才对 -我不是说薇莉!
-She's your friend, you tell me. -I'm not talking about Violet!
-她责怪我 -为了什么?
-She blames me for something. -For what?
-她母亲的死 -你杀了她?
-Her mother's death. -Why, did you kill her?
不 她是在离开我后死的
No, no. She died after she left me.
-那她为什么离开你? -她不爱我
-Well why did she leave you? -She didn't love me.
-为什么她不爱你? -我不知道 黛西
-Why didn't she love you? -I don't know, Daisy.
我想人没办法控制这种感情
I don't think people have a lot of control over that sort of thing.
我也不是个好丈夫就是了
As a husband I wasn't much a prize anyway.
不管怎样 她爱上别人了
Whatever the case, she... fell in love with someone else.
谁?
Who?
她的同事我不认识他
A man she used to work with. I didn't know him.
我只看过他一次
I only saw him once.
从远处看到的
From a distance.
他们死于一场车祸
They died in a car accident.
那为什么你的女儿责怪你?
How does your daughter figure that's your fault?
她不知道母亲有外遇
Well, my daughter didn't know about the affair.
责怪我是让她母亲离开的原因
She blamed me for the breakup,
接着导致车祸
and consequently the... car accident.
你没告诉她真相?
Well... did you ever tell her the whole story?
-没 -为什么?
-No. -Why not?
因为我不想让她对母亲的形象破灭
Because I want her to remember her mother the way she does now.
那太蠢了!你真蠢!
That's stupid! You're stupid!
-谢了 -她喜欢周日芭比吗?
-Thank you. -Does your daughter like Barbie Sunday?
-什么? -你的女儿喜欢歌手周日芭比吗?
-What? -Does your daughter like Barbie Sunday?
很喜欢
Very much.
至少你做对了件事
Well, at least you did somethin' right.
现在我要去找些子弹 把事情做个结束
Now, I'm gonna get some bullets and be done with all this.
跟薇莉讲
Tell Violet.
光合作用
你喜欢我伙伴?
You like my partner, don't you?
为什么不呢?她是个好女孩
What's not to like? She's… a sweet girl.
你喜欢她胜过我?
Do you like her better than me?
我对你又不了解
I don't know you as well.
没关系
That's okay.
我也喜欢她胜过自己
I'd like her better than me too. She might even
她甚至想说不杀了你真是孩子气…
think she can keep you alive for some silly reason. Kids...
-我可以问个问题吗? -问吧
-May I ask you a question, Violet? -You may ask.
你会不会想念玩偶医院?
Do you ever miss the Doll hospital?
还好
Not particularly.
我知道你想要说什么
And I think I know what you're driving at, mister.
但是这工作从来没让我情绪激动过
But this job never got to me,
除了下手时的快感
aside from the sensational rush of the action.
-那些人怎么办? -什么人?
-What about those men? -What men?
那些被你杀的人
The ones you killed.
那真是太刺激了
That, was fucking magical.
你有看到吗?
Did you see that?
现在说也许太早了
It's a bit early to know, but career-wise...
但那也许是我职业生涯的"蒙娜丽莎的微笑"
that little miracle might be my Mona Lisa.
甚至是我的"比莉珍"(麦克杰克森的著名歌曲)
If not my Billie Jean.
-事实上… -你有家人吗?
-Actually... -Do you have any family?
什么?
What?
你有家人吗?
Do you have any family?
-真是奇怪的问题 -那你有吗?
-What a random question. -Well, do you?
黛西就像我的家人
Daisy's like family.
你没回答我的问题
You didn't answer the question.
我父亲可能还活着为什么要问这些?
I got a father somewhere. What's with the interview?
你上次跟他讲话是多久以前的事?
When's the last time you and he spoke?
-关你什么事? -所以很久
-What do you care? -That long huh?
-你会担心接下来会怎样吗? -担心被枪杀?
-Are you afraid of what's next? -Me getting shot?
我是说死了后
I mean after that.
我有想过
I've thought about it.
然后?
And?
没得出什么结论
I haven't come up with anything conclusive.
虽然我不是这方面的专家 但我有个理论
I'm not an expert or anything, but I have a theory.
嗯?
Yeah?
我想…
I figure...
我想天堂是…
I figure heaven... is probably a place where...
那里没有人会在你的外表
nobody cares how big or small you are, or what you look like.
甚至可能没有身体
People probably don't even have bodies.
他们可能只是虚无飘缈的灵魂
They're just maybe like... essences or something.
不过如果他们真的有身体的话 那一定全身赤裸
But if they do have bodies, everyone's gotta be naked for sure,
因为我们就是这样来到这世界的
'cause that's we all showed up here in the first place, right?
而且如果你会背痛
And also, if you have a back problem,
或膝盖疼 或缺乏自信心
or bad knees or self-esteem issues,
这些都不会再困扰你了
that stuff wouldn't bother you anymore up there.
而且东西都是免费的
And everything's free too.
要不然至少会很便宜
Or at least whole sale.
如果有动物的话就更好了
I don't know if there are animals, but that would be cool.
对了
Oh yeah,
当你第一次经过天国之门的时候
and when you walkin' in through the gates for the very first time.
他们还会一边播放路易斯阿姆斯壮的那首歌
They're probably playin' that Louis Armstrong song.
或类似的歌
Somethin' nice like that.
这些想法有些来自我认识的一个女生
Part of it came from this girl I knew.
她已经死了
She died.
很复杂的故事
It's a long story.
是她认为每个人都会赤裸
Anyway, she thought everybody would be naked. That part was her idea.
-她怎么死的? -我不想讲
-How did she die? -I don't wanna talk about it!
我想 但是…
I mean, I do but...
每次都让我讲不下去
when I try it never works.
也许改天吧
Maybe someday.
哇
Wow!
坐起来
Sit up.
谁想要吃点心?
Who wants some snack?
你知道吗?
You know what?
哇
Wow!
什么?
What?
这里的弹孔太少了
I don't think there are enough holes here,
我跟黛西扫射的不只这些才对
from that first time me and Daisy came out blastin'.
这重要吗?
Is that important?
有可能
Could be.
她可能没有尽到她的义务
In any case I have a feeling that my partner's not exactly holdin' up her end.
我从没…
I've never...
真的…
actually...
真的杀过任何人
really ever killed anybody.
我一直用空包弹
I've been using blanks.
然后确保我的子弹跟薇莉的不会混在一起
I just make sure me and Violet don't share ammunition.
因为她是如此的投入工作
Like I said, she's so fierce and thorough on the job.
就算我拿的是水枪也没差
I could pack a squirt gun. It just wouldn't matter.
"没有尽到义务"是指什么?
How do you mean, "holding up her end?"
也许我是唯一有在杀人的
I mean that I might be the only one takin' out the trash.
-也许她一直都用空包弹 -那又怎样?
-Means it looks like she's been packin' blanks. -So what?
-又怎样? -对 那又怎样?
-So what?! -Yeah, so what?
就算她没杀到人 她跟在你身边也有好处
Even if she isn't taking people out, isn't it better that she's with you?
让对手必须要瞄准两个而不是一个
Do you think your opponent's having two targets instead of one
也许你因此而逃过几劫
might've saved your behind a time or two?
她也是冒着生命危险
Do you understand, she's risking her life as well?
她的友谊也可以让你不致丧失人性
Do you think your friendship might've helped keep you sane...
-当你做着这样的工作 -这是诚信问题
-as you wander through this life of yours? -There is still the principle.
她的行为在这行业是不能被接受的
We have rules and what she may have been doin'
不管你怎么轻描淡写
is a big no-no, no matter how you slice it.
今天也许只是偷用空包弹 明天就会偷带窃听器
'Cause one day you're packin' blanks and the next you're wearin' a wire.
那你要怎样?
So what are you going to do about it?
如果这是真的 我就必须杀了她
I'm gonna have to take her out, if my suspicion is true.
我还以为她是你的朋友
I thought Daisy was your friend.
我没说我不会伤心
I'm not sayin' I'm gonna like it.
你不是说她甚至是家人?
I thought you said she was like family?
她是
She is.
不过她也是职业妇女 她会理解的
But she's a business woman too, so she'll understand.
反正我也一直相信她会早死
I always figured she'd check out first anyway.
为什么?
Why?
因为好人通常都会早死
'Cause that's how it usually goes for the good ones.
你有吹风机吗?
You got a hair dryer?
萝丝归来
42号
Unit 42, come in.
42号 回答
Unit 42, respond to dispatch.
你来晚了
You just missed her.
-小黛? -她才刚离开
-Daze? -She just left.
谁?
Who?
萝丝
Rose.
-她活着? -我不知道
-Was she alive? -I don't know.
但她问到你
But she asked about you.
她说了什么?
What did she say?
她说:我在找你的伙伴
She said: "I'm looking for your partner."
一字不差
Those were her exact words.
-只有这样? -不
-Is that all she said? -No.
还说 萝丝死了 薇莉也是
She said that roses were dead, and violets were too.
然后她就离开了
She's split after that and that was the end of it.
你在这里多久了?
How long have you been here?
她比我想像的还高
She's taller than I thought.
小黛 你在这里多久了?
How long have you been here, Daze?
我不确定
I can't really tell.
因为时间产生了扭曲
Time is bent up now, so I don't know.
让我一直错过班机
I keep missing my flights.
那是什么?
What's that?
那个?
Oh, that?
那是那个男人的
That's his. The guy's.
萝丝回来了
Rose is back.
九除一
嗨 九号
Hello, Number 9.
天
Oh my!
你就是?
Are you...?
哇
Wow!
-我一直以为你是… -是什么?
-I always figured you were... -You always figured I was what?
虚构的
Imaginary.
或男的
Or a boy.
知道我今天都在做什么吗?
Do you know what I've been doing today?
一直监视你们
I've been watching you and your partner.
你有听到什么吗?
Did you hear somethin'?
你的朋友行事太疯狂了
That partner of yours is clean out of her mind.
她会给我们带来麻烦
And she's gonna put us all in a real bad spot.
我们不能允许她这样
And we can't let that happen.
我不能允许她这样
I can't let that happen.
我不会允许她这样
I won't let that happen.
你知道她的大屠杀会造成什么麻烦吗?
Do you even know what grief her little slaughter is gonna cost us?
我告诉你
Well, I'll tell you.
两个被她杀的人已经订婚了
Two of the idiots that she ventilated were engaged.
他们娶的人是谁知道吗?
Do you know who they were gonna marry?
警察局长的继女
The Police Chief's stepdaughters.
所以当他们查出真相后
And you can bet the house that once they sort out all these rubbish
老板就有麻烦了
Boss is gonna be held accountable.
接下来就会战火四起
Next to that, a garden variety gang war would be a Sunday stroll.
-楼下有个死人 -他看到了我
-There was a dead guy at the bottom of the steps. -He saw me!
我可以问个问题吗?
Can I ask you a question, ma'am?
你都自己一个人吗?
Do you always work by yourself?
对
Yes.
会孤独吗?
Is it lonely?
问这干嘛?
What's that to you?
好奇而已
Just wondering.
那就回到正事 不然我上芭蕾舞课要迟到了
Well then, let's get back to business, 'cause I'm late for my ballet class.
完成任务 要不后果自负
Finish the job or face the consequences.
清楚了吗?
Am I clear?
嗯…
Well...
一号 我跟你讲
I got news for you, Number One.
我能理解你为什么如此生气
Given the situation, I see why you're T.O.'d and all.
但覆水难收
But, what's done is done.
而且我很重视我伙伴
And my partner comes first.
-你要说什么? -我要说的是
-What's that supposed to mean? -It means...
如果你想要杀她 或是插手我们的任务
that if you try to take her out or get into the middle of our job,
你就要麻烦大了
you're in for a world of hurt!
我知道你很行 但我们也是专家
I know what you're capable of, but we're pros too.
而且我们现在会有所戒备
We also know that you're comin' now.
你知道我在你这年纪的时候想做什么吗?
Do you know what I wanted to be when I was your age?
我也不知道
I don't either.
我欣赏你
I like you kid.
即使你知道自己是在虚张声势
You're in over your head and you're scared,
而且吓得要死 但你还是能直视死亡而不颤抖
yet you look death in the eye without blinking.
非常值得尊敬 但这却救不了你
It's admirable, but it won't save you.
也救不了你的朋友
It won't save your partner
或你的新朋友
and it won't save your new pal.
完成任务 要不后果自负
Finish the job or face the consequences.
你有一小时
You've got an hour.
很抱歉我之前说的那些话
Sorry about that stuff I said before.
哪些话?
What stuff?
我说你很笨之类的
When I called you stupid and stuff.
那没什么
That's okay.
你有找到子弹吗?
Did you find anymore bullets laying around?
嗨
Hey.
想知道件事吗?
Wanna hear somethin'?
你的女儿不恨你
Your daughter doesn't hate you.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
我知道
I know.
是怎么知道的?
Well how could you?
你从没见过她
You've never even met her.
那不重要
Doesn't matter.
我就是知道她不恨你
I still know she doesn't hate you.
为什么?
How?
我也是个女儿
I'm a daughter too.
小薇
Vi?
她离开了
She left.
去哪?
Where'd she go?
去找子弹
To get more bullets.
记住我的话
Listen carefully, Daisy.
当她回来后
When she comes back,
你必须是杀了我的那个人
I need for you to be the one to put me down.
这非常重要
It's very important.
为什么是我?
Why me?
因为你跟我是朋友
'Cause you and me are friends, right?
-是没错 但… -你能答应我吗?
-I guess, but... -Will you promise me that?
-我不能 -我要你答应我
-I can't. -I need you to promise me.
-但我不能 -我真的要你来动手
-But I can't. -I need you to do this for me.
-我不能 -我真的要你来动手
-I can't. -I need you to do this for me!
-不!我不行! -不要反对我!艾波!
-No, I can't! -Don't argue with me, April!
-我是黛西 -反正不要反对我!
-But I'm Daisy. -Just don't argue with me girl!
答应我
You promise me.
说
Say it.
-我答应 -你答应了?
-I promise. -You promise?
我说了不是吗?
I said I would, didn't I?
我有东西给你看
I have something to show you.
我想给我女儿 但她扔回来给我
I tried to give it to my daughter, but she... threw it back at me.
你的尺寸应该跟她差不多
I think you're about her size.
你可以穿看看吗?
Could you try it on?
我会在隔壁房间等
I'll wait in the other room.
永生不朽
拿到子弹了
Got the bullets.
找了一堆地方才终于…
You'd be surprised how many places I...
发生什么事了?
What's goin' on?
我看起来怎样?
How do I look?
还可以从哪里拿的?
Okay. Where did you get it?
他给我的
He gave it to me.
为什么?
What for?
我不知道
I don't know, Vi.
我要跟你讲下话
Can I talk to you a minute?
你是疯了吗?
Have you lost your mind?
-你有什么问题? -你就是我的问题
-What's your problem? -You're my problem!
我会借给你的 如果是因为这样的话
I'll let you borrow it some time if that's what this is about.
不是衣服的问题!
No, it's not about a fucking dress!
-最好是 -就是这样!
-Yeah, right. -That's exactly right!
你不能控制我我们不认识别人
You don't run me, Violet! We don't know anybody,
或参与任何社交活动
or get involved in stuff or anything like that.
我没有参加过毕业舞会 你却有
I never went to a prom. You did, but I didn't.
-没去过才好 -为什么?
-Be glad you didn't! -Why?
-因为他们会取笑你! -你怎么知道?
-Because they would laugh at you! -How do you know?
因为奇怪的人就是会被取笑
Because that's what they do if you're different.
不是每个人都会这样的 再说就算被取笑又怎样
Everybody isn't like that, Vi. And so what if they laugh?
-又怎样! -不要以为你比我懂
-So what? -Don't tell me what I know.
你没尝过我经历过什么
You haven't been through things like me.
如果那会让我怕人的话 我很庆幸我没经历过
And I hope I never do if it makes me so scared.
-我才没怕人! -你有
-I'm not scared! -Yes you are, Violet.
你不相信任何人或任何事
You don't trust anyone, or anything.
从不
You never did.
我曾经相信你!
I trusted you!
什么?
What?
我说 我曾经相信过你!
I said I trusted you!
什么时候不信的?
When did you stop?
当我看到你穿上这件衣服的时候!
The second I saw that goddamn dress on your back!
这样太完美了
Well that's just perfect then.
为什么?
Why?
因为你终于什么都没有了
Because now you don't have anything at all.
-你到底想说什么? -我刚刚不是说了
-So what are you trying to say? -I just said it.
有种就再说一次
Say it again, if you have the guts.
-不要! -我要揍死你!
-You heard me! -I'm gonna kick your ass!
住手!你会弄破我的新衣服!
Cut it out bitch! You're gonna mess up my new dress.
我的房东刚经过
My landlady was coming up the street.
我只是…
I was just...
想吓她一下
just messin' with her.
从没开过枪
Never shot a gun before.
感觉怎样?
How was it?
你现在想要新鞋?
What are you, angling for some new shoes now?
-住口! -你才住口!
-Shut up about it! -You shut up about it!
-来啊! -我刚刚不是就做了!
-Make me! -I just did!
-才这种程度? -薇莉
-Oh, is that what you call it? -Violet!
什么?
What?
差点忘了 我也有东西要给你
I almost forgot. I got something for you too.
真的?
Really?
-为什么要给我这个? -因为你看世界的眼光很奇特
-Why are you giving this to me? -You have a unique world view.
现在你可以跟人分享了
Now you can share with others... in a new way.
谢谢
Thanks a lot, mister.
我需要警察
I need the police.
是的 哪就是我的住址
Yes, that's my address.
你在做什么?
What are you doin'?
他在写信
He's writing a letter.
给水?
To who?
给"谁"
To whom?
给谁?
His daughter.
他的女儿
我来好了
I'll do it.
什么?
What?
我帮你写
I'll write it for you.
好啊
Alright.
谢谢
Thank you.
我写到哪?
So where was I?
亲爱的艾波
"Dear April..."
就这样?
That's it?
对
So far, yeah.
"亲爱的艾波"
"Dear April,
我不知道你会不会读到这封信
I don't know if you'll ever read this,
但我希望你会
but I hope you do.
不管怎样…
In any case...
我们还是对话到了
It's time we finally talk.
好好照顾你自己
Please, take care of yourself.
我设法汇了些钱到你的帐户
I managed to put some money in your bank accounts.
请用这些钱继续求学
Please use it to continue your education.
你的母亲也会这样希望的
Your mother would've wanted that too.
不要太在意浴室里的那些尸体
Don't worry about the dead men in the bathtub.
那不是表面上看来的那样
It's not what it looks like.
但我现在没时间解释
And a long story to tell right now.
有时候
Sometimes,
不知怎么的
for no particular reason,
我就会想起你
I think of you
然后微笑
and smile.
特别是那天
Seriously about that day, that...
我们开车去购物中心
we drove out to the mall,
去庆祝你的生日
for your birthday.
你的母亲因为感冒了
Your mom had the flu,
所以叫我们自己去
and she said to go on without her.
我记得你不小心走开
I remember you wandered off.
然后迷路了
Got lost.
过了两个小时
And two hours later,
我才找到你
we finally found each other.
我们拥抱
We hugged...
你迟迟不肯放开
You didn't wanna let go.
接着我们去吃了冰淇淋
Then we went for ice cream,
我们一直聊个不停 直到回家为止
and we talked... all the way home.
那是我最快乐的一天
I think that was the happiest day I've had.
我知道我不是世界上最好的父亲
I know I probably wasn't the best father in the world,
但我非常尽力的做到最好
but I tried the best I could.
不管怎样…
Anyway...
我毫无保留的爱你
I've loved you all that I possibly can.
爱你的父亲上
Love, Dad."
备注
"PS:
这不是我的笔迹
This isn't in my handwriting,
因为我的朋友
because friend of mine
说要帮我写
wrote it out for me."
如果你们走之前把信放在这
If you just leave that in the...
她就会拿到了
apartment when you go, it's sure to get to her.
幸好你们有来
Glad you girls came by.
不然我就不会写下这封信了
I wouldn't have written that otherwise.
小黛
Daze...
我们必须走了
We gotta go now, Daze.
我甚至没叫过他的名字
He never even said his name, Vi.
走吧
Come on.
脚踏车不见了
The bike is gone.
我知道
I know.
周日芭比新衣服发售中!
-我们终于买到了 -对啊
-Well, we got 'em. -Yep.
-你穿起来很漂亮 -你也是
-Yours looked awesome on you. -Yeah, so did yours.
在那天之后…我们就没有好好说过话
Hey, I know we never really talked about stuff... since that day.
我们之间没问题吧?
Are we cool?
当然
Yeah. Of course.
很好
Righteous.
你会饿吗?
Hey, you hungry or anything?
不会我想要散个步
Not really. I'm just gonna take a walk.
我也不饿
Yeah, screw food.
其实我很想睡
I could use a nap if you wanna know the truth.
要我帮你把东西拿回家吗?
You want me to take your bag home?
不用
No.
最好不是鲁斯
This better not be Russ.
是我爸
It's my dad.
真的?
Really?
本来是想打电话叫披萨 最后却打给他
I tried to get the pizza place, but I... I pressed his number instead.
一言难尽
Long story.
等一下
Hang on a sec, Phil.
再见
See you, Daze!
老爸
Hey dad.
最后一件事
艾波?
April?
你是艾波吗?
Are you... uhm, April?
嗨
Hi.
我是你父亲的朋友
I was a friend of your father's.
我想让你知道…
I just wanted to let you know that...
我是他的朋友 而且…
I was a friend of his and...
他很喜欢说起你的事
that he talked about you a lot.
他想要我给你个东西
He wanted me to give something to you too.
这是什么?
What is it?
是最新的周日芭比衣服
It's the new Barbie Sunday dress.
-真的? -真的
-For real? -Yeah.
尺寸应该没问题
I think it should fit.
里面还有别的东西
There's something else in there too.
谢了
Thanks.
不客气
You're welcome.
你父亲是个很好的人
Your father was a good guy, April.
他有说起 你们在大卖场迷路 然后吃冰淇淋的故事
He told me how you two got lost in the mall one day and then had ice cream.
那个…
Well...
再见了
See ya.